{"tossups": [{"question": "This man was forced to recognize Alexander III as pope after signing the Peace of Venice. In one battle, the \u201cCompany of Death\u201d successfully defended Aribert\u2019s<em> carroccio</em> from this man. This man\u2019s attempt to control the papacy was thwarted at Legnano by the Lombard League. In another campaign, this man drowned in the Saleph River before he could join the forces of Philip Augustus and Richard I. Named for his red beard, for ten points, identify this Holy Roman Emperor who died on the Third Crusade.", "answer": "<b> Frederick I</b> (accept<b> Frederick Barbarossa</b>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "One character in this work becomes pregnant after a head in a calabash tree spits in her hand. This work begins with a creation story where wooden people are killed in a flood. In this work, one character has his head stolen by Camazotz when he\u2019s decapitated in the House of the Bats, which he visits after the House of Dark and the House of Cold. The Hero Twins become the sun and moon after defeating the lords of Xibalba by winning the ball game in, for ten points, what Mayan collection of myths?", "answer": "The<b> Popol Vuh</b>", "metadata": "Mythology - Mythology"}, {}, {}, {"question": "One leader of this country declared that \u201cthe revolution has no winners and no losers\u201d and used the policy of Chehabism. Bashir Gemayel led the left wing Kataeb Phalange Party in this country, where a 1958 crisis prompted Dwight Eisenhower to authorize a U.S. intervention for Camille Chamoun in Operation Blue Bat. This country\u2019s 1943 National Pact shares power between Sunni and Shia Muslims, Greek Orthodox and Maronite Christians, and Druze in, for ten points, what country centered at Beirut?", "answer": "<b> Lebanon</b> Page 1", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "A general of this dynasty wrote the lyrical poem Man Jiang Hong. That general serving this dynasty had four words tattooed onto his back and was named Yue Fei. This dynasty was the first to establish a permanent navy, although its last emperor drowned at the Battle of Yamen. The Jingkang Incident began the Southern period of this dynasty, which lost its capital Kaifeng to the Jurchen-led Jin dynasty. For ten points, name this dynasty conquered by the Mongol Yuan dynasty.", "answer": "<b> Song</b> Dynasty (Accept<b> Northern Song</b> until \u201cSouthern Period\u201d)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "A chord made up of the notes F, B, D-sharp, and G-sharp is named for an operatic character of this composer. Ludwig II\u2019s design of Neuschwanstein Castle contains many references to the works of this composer. This composer, who wrote the controversial essay \u201cJewishness in Music,\u201d wrote an opera with excerpted numbers such as \u201cElsa\u2019s Procession to the Cathedral\u201d and the \u201cBridal Chorus.\u201d The Bayreuth Festival honors the operas of, for ten points, what composer of the<em> Ring Cycle</em>?", "answer": "Richard<b> Wagner</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Auditory Fine Arts"}, {"question": "In the aftermath of this event, Edward Teller wrote that Jane Fonda suffering a heart attack was the only victim of it. John Kemeny led an investigation in this event which found that a similar occurrence at the David-Besse facility should have provided enough warning. A faulty valve created by Babcock and Wilcox was the cause of this event. During this event, a voluntary evacuation near Harrisburg was carried out after the failure of reactor 2. For ten points, name this partial nuclear meltdown that occurred on a Pennsylvania island.", "answer": "<b> Three Mile Island</b> accident Page 2", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This country was the site of the world\u2019s first aerial bombardment when Giulio Gavotti dropped four grenades from his biplane. It\u2019s not Ethiopia, but Rodolfo Graziani forced thousands of this country\u2019s people into concentration camps. The \u201cLion of the Desert,\u201d Omar Mukhtar, led the Senussids in a resistance movement centered on this country\u2019s region of Cyrenaica. Mussolini\u2019s idea of the \u201cFourth Shore\u201d centered on, for ten points, what country that Italy invaded at Tripolitania?", "answer": "State of<b> Libya</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "A member of this family wrote a work which criticized the \u201cArbitrary Government\u201d erected \u201cUnder Sir Edmund Andros.\u201d Zabdiel Boylston was convinced by a member of this family, who himself was inspired by his slave Onesimus, to inoculate hundreds of people against smallpox. During one event, a member of this family warned against a reliance on \u201cspectral evidence\u201d and later wrote to William Stoughton congratulating him for extinguishing devilism. For ten points, name this Massachusetts Puritan family which included \u201cIncrease\u201d and \u201cCotton\u201d.", "answer": "<b> Mather</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "The basis of this initiative was laid out in a report by Lewis H. Brown which included a plan to break the \u201cvicious coal cycle.\u201d The formulator of this initiative claimed that the \u201cthe division of labor...is in danger of breaking down\u201d while advocating for this plan at a Harvard commencement address. This plan replaced an earlier one devised by Henry Morgenthau which dictated that no steps be taken to rehabilitate the German economy. For ten points, name this plan, named for Harry Truman\u2019s Secretary of State, to rebuild Europe in the aftermath of World War II.", "answer": "<b> Marshall</b> plan (accept<b> European Recovery Program</b>; accept<b> ERP</b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "This country\u2019s sovereignty was threatened by the USSR during the Note Crisis. Nikita Khrushchev declared that this country\u2019s relations with the USSR had deteriorated to a \u201cnight frost\u201d in 1958. The Paasikvi-Kekkonen Doctrine preserved relations between this country and both NATO and the Warsaw Pact. Gerald Ford and Leonid Brezhnev signed a 1975 agreement in this country\u2019s capital intended to ease Cold War tensions. For ten points, name this country where the Helsinki Accords were signed.", "answer": "Republic of<b> Finland</b> (accept<b> Suomen tasavalta</b> or Republiken<b> Finland</b>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "Jawed Mojaddedi undertook a recent effort to translate this author into English. A translator of this author, Coleman Barks, sparked controversy for not knowing the language that this author wrote in. This author wrote \u201cThe Song of The Reed Flute\u201d and featured a poem that ended each line with a Greek word in his collection<em> Divan</em>. This author wrote the 50,000 line<em> Masnavi</em> in his native language, Farsi. For ten points, name this Sufi poet and author of Spiritual Couplets.", "answer": "Jalal al-Din Muhammad<b> Rumi</b> (accept Jalal al-Din Muhammad<b> Rumi</b>)", "metadata": "Literature - World Literature - Poetry"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>Sophie Wahnich argues that 18th and 20th century political uses of this word differ in the</b> <b>sacrality of citizenship in a work titled</b><em><b> In Defense of [this word]</b></em><b>. Giovanna (+)</b> <b>Borradori</b> <b>claimed that a phenomenon described by this word was a rejection of Enlightenment ideas in a work involving J\u00a8urgen Habermas and Jacques Derrida. This word\u2019s political use was popularized in a conservative backlash led by Edmund (*) </b> Burke to a period named for this word, where one participant claimed this word would be \u201cthe order of the day.\u201d For ten points, what word names a reign during the French Revolution?", "answer": "<b> \u201cterror\u201d</b> (accept<b> terrorism</b>)", "metadata": "Philosophy - Philosophy"}, {"question": "<b>While on the way to the Malakand Campaign, this man wrote of the Lauranian dictator Antonio Molara in</b><em><b> Savrola</b></em><b>. This man described fighting with the 21st Lancers at the Battle</b> <b>of Omdurman under Lord (+)</b> <b>Kitchener in his work</b><em><b> The River War</b></em><b>. This man wrote</b> <b>about his ancestor, in</b><em><b> Marlborough: His Life and Times</b></em><b> and late in his life produced the four-volume (*) </b> <em>History of the English Speaking Peoples</em>. One of his speeches borrowed a Giuseppe Garibaldi phrase to state that \u201cI have nothing to offer but blood, toil, tears, and sweat.\u201d For ten points, name this British prime minister during WWII.", "answer": "Winston<b> Churchill</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>Two answers required. V.K. Menon was forced to resign as Minister of Defense after a conflict between these two countries broke out. A series of outposts near the border between</b> <b>these two countries were built under the (+)</b> <b>Forward Policy, despite both countries</b> <b>agreeing to the Five Principles of Peaceful Coexistence. One country granting asylum to the Dalai Lama after the 1959 (*) </b> Tibetan Uprising resulted in a 1962 border war between these two countries. Aksai Chin remains contentious between, for ten points, what two countries formerly led by Jawaharlal Nehru and Mao Zedong?", "answer": "People\u2019s Republic of<b> China</b> and Republic of<b> India</b> (accept<b> PRC</b> for \u201cChina\u201d) Page 9", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b>Margaret of Savoy tried to calm demonstrators in this city but was ultimately forced out of the country. The Battle of (+) Alcantara was fought outside this city, ending its country\u2019s independent rule. While returning to this city\u2019s Ajuda Hills, a royal carriage was fired upon during an assassination attempt on Joseph I, which resulted in the (*)</b> Tavora family\u2019s public execution. The Marquis of Pombal oversaw this city\u2019s reconstruction following an earthquake on All Saints Day in 1755. The mouth of the Tagus River is in, for ten points, what capital city of Portugal?", "answer": "<b> Lisbon</b> (or<b> Lisboa</b>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>After his dog fell in a hole, Marcel Ravidat discovered this location, which he thought was a secret passage to a local manor. Abb\u00b4e Henri Breuil sketched this location, which includes the (+)</b><em><b> Chamber of the Felines</b></em><b> and the</b><em><b> Hall of the Bulls</b></em><b>. Ochre and hematite, as</b> <b>well as (*)</b> charcoal would have been used to decorate this location, which includes a painting called \u201cThe Crossed Bison\u201d featuring primitive use of perspective. For ten points, name this French Upper Paleolithic site, which includes many wall drawings.", "answer": "<b> Lascaux</b> cave", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Visual Fine Arts"}, {"question": "<b>This man\u2019s illegitimate daughter, Essie Mae Washington-Williams, revealed her identity at age 78. Trent Lott praised this man in 2002 claiming that, had we elected him, the US wouldn\u2019t have had so many problems. During his campaign for governor, this man opposed</b> <b>the (+)</b> <b>Barnwell Ring.\u201d This man was the first Senator to win as a write-in candidate. In</b> <b>Barnwell Ring.\u201d This man was the first Senator to win as a write-in candidate. In</b> <b>the 1948 election, this man led a party that commonly used the (*)</b> <b>the 1948 election, this man led a party that commonly used the (*)</b> Confederate battle flag. The Dixiecrat Party was led by, for ten points, what long-time Senator from South Carolina who, in the face of the Civil Rights Act of 1957, delivered a 24-hour filibuster?", "answer": "Strom<b> Thurmond</b> Page 10", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>A legend about a prostitute and a glass-eyed delegate from this state surrounds the move of this state\u2019s capital four times in a 25 year period. 1,300 miners</b><em><b> from</b></em><b> this</b> <b>state were kidnapped and brought to a neighboring state in the 1917 (+)</b> <b>Bisbee</b> <b>Deportation. The westernmost battle of the Civil War, the Battle of Pichaco Pass, took place in this modern-day state. This state\u2019s (*)</b> \u201cSilent Senator,\u201d Carl Hayden, was the first Senator to serve seven terms. For ten points, name this last contiguous state to be admitted to the union whose capital and largest city is Phoenix.", "answer": "<b> Arizona </b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}], "bonuses": []}